Guide to the National Committee to Reopen the Rosenberg Case Records TAM.174
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series III. Promotional Materials, 1944-2005; 1975-1997; 12.5 Linear Feet in 10 record cartons, 1 tall manuscript box, and 1 oversize flat box.
  - Newsletters and Mailers, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Rosenberg Material, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence and Promotional Materials, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Newsletter Draft, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 6-7)
  - Correspondence and Newspaper Clippings, 1993-1998 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Newsletters and Newsletter Drafts, 1993-2005 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Promotional Materials, Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, Newsletters, Newsletter Drafts, 1993-1994 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence and Newsletter Drafts, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence and Promotional Materials Drafts, 1993-1995 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Newsletters, Newspaper Clippings, Correspondence, 1993-1997 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Newsletter Drafts, circa 1993 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Newsletters, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Newsletters, 1993-1994 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Newsletters and Correspondence, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Newsletters and Correspondence, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - ABA Rosenberg Mock Trial, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 20-21)
  - ABA Rosenberg Mock Trial Transcript, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 22-23)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Newsletters, Correspondence, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - France, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Newsletters and Newspaper Clippings, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Pamphlets and Annual Reports from Other Organizations, 1995, 2001, 2005 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Defendants Rosenberg by Ari Benjamin Meyers, 1996 (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - Newsletters, Correspondence, Newspaper Clippings, Articles/Papers, 1996-1998 (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Pamphlets from Other Organizations, 1996, 2000-2001 (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - Promos for Rosenberg-inspired Plays, 1996 (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence and Promotional Materials from Other Organizations, 1997-1998 (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - Dictum, 1997-2000 (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - Newsletters and Newsletter Drafts, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - Newsletters and Newsletter Drafts, 1997-2002 (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - Newsletter, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 36)
  - Newsletter Materials and Correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 16, Folder 37)
  - Newspaper Clippings and Newsletters, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and Newspaper Clippings, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings and Newsletters, 1997, 2005 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, Correspondence, 1997-2003 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Newsletter Materials, 1997-1998 (Box 17, Folder 6-8)
  - Correspondence, Newsletters, Photograph, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Newsletters, Correspondence, Newsletter and Article Drafts, 2000-2003 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Abel Meeropol Event and Correspondence, 2001, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - La Peur, by Georges Soria, circa 2001 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Newsletters, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Newsletters and Correspondence, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Newspaper Clippings and Rosenberg Fund for Children Newsletters, 2003-2004 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Newsletters and Memorial Program, 2003-2004 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - French Petition to Re-examine the Rosenberg Case, 2004 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Newsletters, 2004 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Buttons, circa 1976 (Box 18)
  - "Reopening the Past in Light of the Present" Poster, 1974 (Box Shared Tamiment 057, Folder 3)
  - Carnegie Hall Anniversary Event Poster, 1976 (Box Shared Tamiment 057, Folder 4)
  - 35th Commemoration Poster, 1988 (Box Shared Tamiment 057, Folder 5)
  - Publications – We Are Your Sons: The Legacy of Ethel and Julius Rosenberg by Robert and Michael Meeropol, 1975 (Box 19)
  - Publications – The Rosenberg Letters: A Complete Edition of the Prison Correspondence of Julius and Ethel Rosenberg, 1994 (Box 19)
  - Publications – Federal Criminal Law Revision: Hearings before the Subcommittee on Criminal Justice of the Committee on the Judiciary, House of Representatives, Ninety-seventh Congress, First and Second Sessions, on H.R. 1647, H.R. 4492, H.R. 4711, H.R. 5679, and H.R. 5703, 1983 (Box 19)
  - Publications – The Murder of the Rosenbergs by Stanley Yalkowsky, 1990 (Box 19)
  - Publications – Framing History: The Rosenberg Story and the Cold War by Virginia Carmichael, 1993 (Box 19)
  - Audiovisual Material – The Unquiet Death of Julius and Ethel Rosenberg, 1975 (Reel 1, Reel 2, Reel 3, Reel 4)
  - Audiovisual Material – We Are Innocent by Leonard Lehrman, circa 1989 (Box 19)
  - Audiovisual Material – Defendants Rosenberg by Ari Benjamin Meyers, 1996 (Box Shared Tamiment 056)
  - Audiovisual Material – Songs of Conscience by Edith Segal & Leonard Lehrman, 1991 (Box Shared Tamiment 067)
  - Audiovisual Material – Unmarked Audiocassette, circa 1980s-1990s (Box Shared Tamiment 067)
  - Audiovisual Material – Helene Williams Sings Songs of Love, 1998 (Box Shared Tamiment 056)
  - Audiovisual Material – The Abel Meeropol Centennial Concert with the Metropolitan Philharmonic Chorus, 2003 (Box Shared Tamiment 056)
  - Audiovisual Material – The Marc Blitzstein Centennial Concert CD, 2005 (Box Shared Tamiment 056)
- Series IV. Archived Websites, July 2009-November 2014; 547014; 2 websites in 2 archived websites. (Box Electronic Records, E-records https://wayback.archive-it.org/6338/*/http://www.rosenbergtrial.org/, E-records https://wayback.archive-it.org/6338/*/http://ncrrc.org/)
  Scope and Content Note
  The National Committee to Reopen the Rosenberg Case (NCRRC) was established to win an official review of the trial and exoneration of Julius and Ethel Rosenberg.
  Between 2010 and 2011, the NCRRC changed their website URL. Both iterations of the website contain extensive background information, photographs, and resources on the trial, the events surrounding it, and the people and players involved. The websites also include news updates and publicity on the work of the committee, contact information, and information on how to donate and take action. Some of the later captures from 2013 and 2014 contain Flash components that may not run.